{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers can be used to describe self-signed digital certificates? (Select 3 answers)",
      "options": [
        "Backed by a well-known and trusted third party",
        "Not trusted by default by web browsers and other applications",
        "Used in trusted environments, such as internal networks and development environments",
        "Suitable for websites and other applications that are accessible to the public",
        "Trusted by default by web browsers and other applications",
        "Not backed by a well-known and trusted third party"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "Not trusted by default by web browsers and other applications",
        "Used in trusted environments, such as internal networks and development environments",
        "Not backed by a well-known and trusted third party"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "A self-signed digital certificate is also referred to as:",
      "options": [
        "Client certificate",
        "EV certificate",
        "Server certificate",
        "Wildcard certificate",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["None of the above"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Third-party digital certificates, issued by trusted CAs, are automatically trusted by most browsers and operating systems, involve a cost, and require validation of the applicant's identity. In contrast, self-signed certificates, issued by the entity to itself, are not automatically trusted, are free to create and use, and do not require validation by a CA.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of digital certificates, the term \"Root of trust\" refers to the highest level of trust within a PKI system. It is typically represented by a root CA, which is a trusted third party that serves as the foundation for the entire PKI. All other entities in the PKI hierarchy, including intermediate CAs and end-entities derive their trust from this root.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a PKI trust model?",
      "options": [
        "Single CA model",
        "Hierarchical model (root CA + intermediate CAs)",
        "Mesh model (cross-certifying CAs)",
        "Web of trust model (all CAs function as root CAs)",
        "Chain of trust model (multiple CAs in a sequential chain)",
        "Bridge model (cross-certifying between separate PKIs)",
        "Hybrid model (combining aspects of different models)",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["All of the above"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to a cryptographic file generated by an entity requesting a digital certificate from a CA?",
      "options": ["OID", "CSR", "DN", "CRL"],
      "correct_answers": ["CSR"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A type of digital certificate that can be used to secure multiple subdomains within a primary domain is known as:",
      "options": [
        "Root signing certificate",
        "Subject Alternative Name (SAN) certificate",
        "Extended Validation (EV) certificate",
        "Wildcard certificate"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["Wildcard certificate"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which digital certificate type allows to secure multiple domain names or subdomains with a single certificate?",
      "options": [
        "Extended Validation (EV) certificate",
        "Wildcard certificate",
        "Subject Alternative Name (SAN) certificate",
        "Root signing certificate"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["Subject Alternative Name (SAN) certificate"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to an identifier used for PKI objects?",
      "options": ["OID", "DN", "SAN", "GUID"],
      "correct_answers": ["OID"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In IT security, the term \"Shadow IT\" is used to describe the practice of using IT systems, software, or services within an organization without the explicit approval or oversight of the organization's IT department.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Match each threat actor type with its common attack vector attribute:",
      "type": "matching",
      "pairs": {
        "Nation-state": "External",
        "Unskilled attacker": "Internal/External",
        "Hacktivist": "External",
        "Insider threat": "Internal",
        "Organized crime": "External",
        "Shadow IT": "Internal"
      }
    },
    {
      "question": "Match each threat actor type with its resources/funding attribute:",
      "type": "matching",
      "pairs": {
        "Nation-state": "High resources and funding",
        "Unskilled attacker": "Low resources and funding",
        "Hacktivist": "Low to medium resources and funding",
        "Insider threat": "Low to high resources and funding",
        "Organized crime": "Medium to high resources and funding",
        "Shadow IT": "Low to medium resources and funding"
      }
    },
    {
      "question": "Match each threat actor type with its level of sophistication:",
      "type": "matching",
      "pairs": {
        "Nation-state": "High level of sophistication",
        "Unskilled attacker": "Low level of sophistication",
        "Hacktivist": "Low to medium level of sophistication",
        "Insider threat": "Low to high level of sophistication",
        "Organized crime": "Medium to high level of sophistication",
        "Shadow IT": "Low to medium level of sophistication"
      }
    },
    {
      "question": "Match each threat actor type with its typical motivations:",
      "type": "matching",
      "pairs": {
        "Nation-state": "Espionage, political/philosophical beliefs, disruption/chaos, war",
        "Unskilled attacker": "Disruption/chaos, financial gain, revenge",
        "Hacktivist": "Ethical beliefs, philosophical/political beliefs, disruption/chaos",
        "Insider threat": "Revenge, financial gain, service disruption",
        "Organized crime": "Financial gain, data exfiltration, extortion",
        "Shadow IT": "Convenience, lack of awareness of security risks, meeting specific needs"
      }
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms is used to describe sophisticated and prolonged cyberattacks often carried out by well-funded and organized groups, such as nation-states?",
      "options": ["MitM", "APT", "XSRF", "DDoS"],
      "correct_answers": ["APT"]
    },
    {
      "question": "An attack surface is the sum of all potential points through which an attacker can interact with a system or network, while a threat vector represents the method by which a cyber threat is delivered. True or False?",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to an email-based threat vector?",
      "options": [
        "Spoofing",
        "Phishing",
        "BEC attacks",
        "Malicious links",
        "Malware attachments",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["All of the above"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms refers to a threat vector commonly associated with SMS-based communication?",
      "options": ["Phishing", "Vishing", "Smishing", "Pharming"],
      "correct_answers": ["Smishing"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to an example of a potential threat vector in IM-based communication?",
      "options": [
        "Phishing attack",
        "Malware distribution",
        "Spoofing attack",
        "Eavesdropping",
        "Account hijacking",
        "Malicious link/attachment",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["All of the above"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refer to examples of image-based threat vectors? (Select 3 answers)",
      "options": [
        "Steganography",
        "BEC attacks",
        "Image spoofing (deepfakes)",
        "Brand impersonation",
        "Malware-embedded images"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "Steganography",
        "Image spoofing (deepfakes)",
        "Malware-embedded images"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a file-based threat vector?",
      "options": [
        "PDF exploits",
        "Malicious macros in documents",
        "Compressed files (ZIP, RAR)",
        "Malicious scripts in web pages",
        "Infected images",
        "Malicious executables",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["All of the above"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answer choices is an example of a threat vector type that is typical for voice communication?",
      "options": ["Smishing", "Pharming", "Vishing", "Phishing"],
      "correct_answers": ["Vishing"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Examples of threat vectors directly related to the use of removable devices include: (Select 2 answers)",
      "options": [
        "Pretexting",
        "Malware delivery",
        "Watering hole attacks",
        "Data exfiltration",
        "Social engineering attacks"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["Malware delivery", "Data exfiltration"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refer(s) to client-based software threat vector(s)? (Select all that apply)",
      "options": [
        "Drive-by download via web browser",
        "Malicious macro",
        "Vulnerability in a network protocol or device",
        "USB-based attack",
        "Infected executable file",
        "Malicious attachment in email application"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "Drive-by download via web browser",
        "Malicious macro",
        "USB-based attack",
        "Infected executable file",
        "Malicious attachment in email application"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refer to agentless software threat vectors? (Select 2 answers)",
      "options": [
        "Phishing email",
        "Malicious USB drive",
        "Network protocol vulnerability",
        "Infected macro",
        "Packet sniffing"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["Network protocol vulnerability", "Packet sniffing"]
    }
  ]
}